SUMMARY

Skilled communicator (Certificate to Mediate in Texas obtained at Southern Methodist University) with management experience internationally and domestically, in teams and on my own. I have managed classrooms full of second graders in Egypt, a family of six(6) in Denver as a Nanny, designed programs about the Middle East and Egypt in Dallas, and I worked to develop a volunteer program at a non profit in Tacoma while also managing their online presence and giving regular presentations to the community through the AmeriCorps Vista program. I constantly receive praise for my ability to communicate and nurture relationships with clients/coworkers. I am goal driven, quick to learn and I am genuine.

Degreed professional with an internationally diverse background skilled in communications with experience implementing and managing structures and programs. Basically, I am really good with people. Detailed listener, engaging presenter, I appreciate the client experience and I am an excellent writer. I work well in teams and on my own.

Inktank Communications-Egypt

Proofread and edited English articles written by non-native speakers Maintained strict deadlines

Cultural Awareness International developed materials Dept of Labor Contract Photographer KVS Law Offices of Ryan Henry

Volunteer: RTSS-AmeriCorps

Nanny

XL Treatment Centers Certification: CNA

Direct Client Care
Photographer

Team management

Nanny

Program Development

CAI DOL

Treatment Centers XL

Summary Skills/Experience Certificates/Education Background

- Degreed professional with a diverse background and an excellent record of performance in customer service, teaching, administrative management, and public relations.
- Multilingual and multicultural with language skills that include Arabic, German, and English.
- Flexible and quickly adaptable to new challenges, enjoys working in a team setting, and can be counted on to attain desired results.
- Extensive computer skills include Macintosh and Windows Microsoft Office suites, Mindmanager, Vertical Response, DreamWeaver, SEO/SEM marketing, Google analytics.

EDUCATION

Completed postgraduate courses in Dispute Resolution and Mediation towards a Master of Arts degree from Southern Methodist University (SMU), 2014.

- Traveled to the 2013 Mediators Beyond Borders Congress in Istanbul, Turkey
- President of Mediators Beyond Borders SMU Chapter

Completed postgraduate courses in Business Administration towards a Master of Business Administration degree with a concentration in Project Management from Colorado Technical University (CTU), 2012

Summa cum laude graduate, Bachelor of Arts in International Diplomacy with a minor in Arabic Culture and Language, University of North Texas, Denton, Texas, May 2009. GPA: 3.8 out of 4.0

- Study abroad:
 - Strathclyde University, Glasgow, Scotland EU and Scottish Politics, European Cold War History, 2008
 - American University Cairo, Cairo Egypt Arabic Language Institute Certification, Summer 2007

Licensure/Certifications:

Texas Certified Mediator

EXPERIENCE

THE LAW OFFICES OF RYAN HENRY P.L.L.C San Antonio, Texas 9/16-6/17

Paralegal- Managed calendar for Junior Associate, followed up with clients, managed client relations, edited legal documents.

- Required intimate knowledge of Microsoft Office
- Required intimate knowledge of English spelling/syntax/grammar
- Required excellent customer service skills which I received much praise for *Supervisor Ryan Henry 201 257 6357*

TRINITY STAFFING San Antonio, Texas

4/16-9/16

Temporary Legal Receptionist- Upon completion of my contract with the staffing agency I was asked to stay on and fulfill the role of paralegal at the Law Offices of Ryan Henry, PLLC

DANCO, Canyon Lake, Texas

8/14 - 8/15

Office Manager – Multifaceted functions involved administrative and customer support for the sales of used farm and construction equipment.

- Managed accounts payable and accounts receivable and worked with customers to resolve billing issues.
- Coordinated documentation for the shipment of equipment to customers throughout the United States.

JENNIFER L. STUART

EXPERIENCE (Continued)

INDEPENDENT CONTRACTOR, Littleton, Colorado

2013

Worked as an Au Pair while pursuing a Master's degree. Managed a household of five children ranging in age from 4 through 16.

THE TREATMENT CENTERS XL, Denver, Colorado

2011 - 2012

Office Manager/Program Manager – Managed front office and clinic operations and staff. Handled administrative tasks that included filing and setting up new patient files.

- Completed daily/biweekly court-ordered urinalysis/breathalyzer tests and prepared reports for review by controlling agencies.
- Collected and managed fees and set up schedules for court-ordered classes and counseling.
- Provided required supervision of drug rehabilitation patients either overnight or 24 hour supervision

REBUILDING TOGETHER SOUTH SOUND, Tacoma, Washington

2010 - 2011

AmeriCorps Volunteer – Wrote and distributed the monthly E-newsletter to over 3,000 contacts and maintained the Website, social media, and organizational Blog.

- Tracked participant progress using Google Analytics.
- Recruited, trained, and managed volunteers.
- Developed the *Ambassador Program* that included orientation, preparation of required forms, and promotional programs for volunteers.
- Developed partnerships with local Veterans groups and organized events for building wheelchair ramps.
- Raised awareness of Affordable Housing within the community and participated in trips to Louisiana to rebuild storm damaged homes.

KNOWLEDGE VALLEY SCHOOL, Cairo, Egypt

2009 - 2010

Teacher – Taught English and Social studies to non-native English speaking students ages 6-9.

INKTANK PUBLICATIONS, Cairo, Egypt

Summer 2009

English Language Editor – Functioned as English Language editor for a financial publication whose articles were drafted in English by native Arabic speakers.

REFERENCES AVAILABLE ON REQUEST